Mupa M'mbetsa Nzaphila

Frontend Developer

mupasmail@gmail.com 📞 +491624735101 👂 Mannheim, Germany

www.mupanzaphila.com in www.linkedin.com/in/mupa-nzaphila () www.github.com/Mupa1

A dedicated frontend developer with 3+ years of experience building intuitive, interactive, and responsive web applications. Proficient in React, Next.js, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and TypeScript with a strong understanding of UI/UX principles. Committed to staying up-to-date with the latest Frontend technologies and best practices.

Professional Experience

Frontend Engineer, ACCURE Battery Intelligence

10/2023 - present

- Developed 100% of the frontend of a new product optimized for performance using React.js.
- Improved overall design of an existing platform enhancing UX and increasing conversion rates by 35%.
- Daily maintained code, debugged and solved issues, ensuring 100% platform stability.
- Collaborated with 2 backend developers to integrate frontend components with RESTful APIs, ensuring 100% data consistency and reliability.

Frontend Engineer, HEYCAR

10/2021 - 09/2023

- Created UI components and configurable reusable input elements that reduced code repetition by 40% on the global commerce checkout.
- Collaborated with designers to ensure the technical feasibility of 15+ UI/UX designs.
- Daily maintained code, debugged and solved issues, ensuring 100% platform stability.
- Increased unit test coverage by 30% on the financing calculator micro-frontend which led to time-saving as bugs got detected early in development.

Frontend Developer, KULIMA

11/2020 - 09/2021

- Created 30+ Figma designs increasing client's confidence in the look and feel of the frontend.
- Developed forms with 100% Validation ensuring correct data collected from user inputs.
- · Leveraged pre-built React components and themes from Material-UI ensuring visual consistency and increasing delivery time by 40%.

Education

Full Stack Web Development, MICROVERSE

01/2020 - 02/2021

Tech Stack: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Databases

Mobile Web Development,

04/2019 - 12/2019

GOOGLE AFRICA DEVELOPER SCHOLARSHIP PROGRAM Tech Stack: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, Databases

Skills

Languages — JavaScript, TypeScript, Ruby, GraphQL, HTML, CSS, SASS

Frameworks & Libraries — React.js, Next.js, Redux, TailwindCSS, Material-UI, Styled Components, Framer Motion, Node.js

Tools & Platforms — Appwrite, Figma, Storybook, Webpack, Vite, Contentful, Git, GitHub, GitLab

Methods — UI Design, Unit Testing, Refactoring, Deployment, CI/CD, Accessibility, UI/UX, Responsive Design, Cross-browser Compatibility